ems.com 2016-05-04

# Privacy Policy

**Effective Date:   May 2015**

Eastern Mountain Sports recognizes that your privacy is important to you. We collect information about you through our websites in order to manage your shopping experience with us and to communicate with you about our products, services, contests and promotions. This policy explains what personal information we collect about you and why; how we will use, share, and protect this information once it is collected; and the choices you can make about our collection and use of your personal information. We encourage you to review this policy to make sure you understand how any personal information you provide to us online will be treated.

We may change this policy from time to time. When we do, we will let you know by posting the changed policy on this page. You can tell if the policy has recently changed by checking the revision date that appears above. In some cases, for example, if we make any significant changes, we may contact you directly about changes to this policy, such as by sending you an e-mail.

**WHAT INFORMATION DOES EASTERN MOUNTAIN SPORTS COLLECT?**

We collect two general types of information from Web site users:  (1) non-personal information concerning the use of our Web sites and (2) personal information that identifies or can be used to identify or contact an individual. Sometimes, we may link Non-Personal Information with Personal Information, in which case it becomes Personal Information.

_Non-Personal Information:_  As is the case with many Web sites, our servers automatically collect your browser type and IP address when you visit one of our Web sites. We may also capture certain clickstream data, which includes, for example, the referring page that linked you to the Eastern Mountain Sports Web site, the pages you visit on our Web site, the next Web site you visit when you leave our Web site, and any search terms you have entered on our Web site or a referral site. 

In addition, we and our third party partners acting on our behalf may use cookies and/or pixel tags to keep track of your visits, preferences and profile information. Cookies are small data files stored on your computer’s hard drive at the request of a Web site, and do not contain personal information about you. Cookies may be used to enhance your experience on our Web sites (including by allowing you to remain logged in); to store some of your preferences; or to collect general usage and aggregated statistical information that does not by itself identify you personally.  Local shared objects, also known as Flash cookies, may also be stored on your hard drive using a media player installed on your computer or device. Flash cookies operate a lot like other cookies, but cannot be managed in the same way as non-Flash cookies.

Any or all of the above-described activities with respect to Non-Personal Information may be performed on our behalf by our service providers.

_Personal Information:   _Most of the Personal Information that we collect from you on our Web sites is what you provide to us. For example, we may collect Personal Information from you, such as your name, e-mail address, postal address, phone number, credit card number, gender, birthday, personal interests, etc., when you place an order online, save your information with us online, sign up for our newsletters, contact us with a question or concern, or participate in a contest, promotion, or survey.

_Information Obtained from Third Parties:_  In some instances, we may supplement and combine the information collected from you with information that is received or otherwise obtained from third parties (whether related to HFTC or not), such as our joint marketing partners.

HOW DOES EASTERN MOUNTAIN SPORTS USE MY INFORMATION?

We and our trusted partners acting on our behalf may use the information (including Personal and Non-Personal Information) we collect from and about you to:

·         process and fulfill your orders, including to send you confirmation and shipment status e-mails

·         communicate with you and to send you information by e-mail, postal mail, telephone, text message, or other means about our products, services, contests, and promotions, unless you have directed us not to contact you with promotional communications

·         administer and fulfill our contests and other promotions

·         help us learn more about your shopping preferences and how we can improve our marketing efforts or your shopping experience with us

·         help us address problems with and develop our site design, products and services

·         conduct research and analysis

·         protect the security or integrity of our websites and our business

·         respond to customer service inquiries, questions, and concerns

You always have the choice not to receive marketing information or calls. To learn how to opt out, please see the  **Opt Out**  section below. 

OPT OUT

You have the right to tell us not to send certain communications to you. For example, you may tell us not to send you our promotional e-mails by clicking on the appropriate link included with any such e-mail you receive from us or by contacting our customer service representatives using the information provided in the  **Contact Us**  section, below. Please note, however, that it may take up to 10 days to process your e-mail request and 6-8 weeks to process your postal mail request, during which period you may continue to receive promotional communications from Eastern Mountain Sports. Moreover, even if you opt out of receiving promotional correspondence from us, we may still contact you in connection with your relationship, activities, transactions and communications with us.

If you change your mind, you can start receiving promotional communications from us again by logging into your online account and changing your preferences, by signing up when you visit our websites or our stores or when you enter a sweepstakes or contest, or by contacting customer service.

SHARING WITH THIRD PARTIES

Eastern Mountain Sports may share your information (including Personal Information and Non-Personal Information) with third parties for a variety of reasons. For example, we share your personal information with trusted third parties who manage our customer information and perform services on our behalf, such as fulfilling promotions, sending communications to our customers, processing credit card transactions, and conducting surveys.  These companies are authorized to use your information only as necessary to provide these services.  In addition, we may share your information:

·         with our parent company, our affiliates, and among our brands

·         with third parties in whose products or services we think you may have an interest

·         as required by law and when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights or those of third parties, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or comply with a court order or other legal process

·         in connection with a corporate change including a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets

·         in connection with co-branded or co-sponsored products, services, contests, or promotions when we team up with others to offer or provide these things to our customers

·         In addition, we may share aggregate Web site usage information that does not identify individual users with third parties for any reason, including, for example, marketing or analytical purposes.

THIRD-PARTY ADVERTISERS

We may use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web sites. These companies may use information about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements that are customized to your interests and preferences. These advertisements may appear on this Web site and on other Web sites.

Please note that some of the advertisers on our Web sites and their and our ad service providers (including advertising network providers and third party ad servers) may deploy cookies or related technologies through their advertising banners, links or other ads. While we use cookies and web beacons on parts of our sites (as discussed above), information received from cookies and other technologies deployed through third party ads and links may be collected directly by those advertisers and ad service providers. The advertiser’s privacy policy and/or that of its service provider will govern the use of this information and we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such companies. Additionally, some of these companies (like the ad networks) are members of the industry group, the Network Advertising Initiative, which offers a single location to opt out of their cookies. For more information, we encourage you to visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer Web site by [clicking here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/)

SECURITY

While we strive to protect the security and integrity of the information provided to us, due to the inherent nature of the Internet as an open global communications vehicle, we cannot guarantee that information, during transmission through the Internet or while stored on our system or otherwise in our care, will be absolutely safe from intrusion by others, such as hackers.

In the unlikely event that we believe that the security of your Personal Information in our possession or control may have been compromised, we may seek to notify you of that development. If a notification is appropriate, we would endeavor to do so as promptly as possible under the circumstances, and, to the extent we have your e-mail address, we may notify you by e-mail.  **Unless you provide us with another method to notify you in this situation, you consent to our use of e-mail as a means of such notification.**

THIRD-PARTY “LINKED-TO” WEB SITES

Our Web sites may contain links, banners, widgets or advertisements that lead to other Web sites. We are not responsible for these other sites, and so their posted privacy policies will govern the collection and use of your information on them. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of the Web sites you visit after leaving any Eastern Mountain Sports Web site to learn about how your information is treated.

CONSENT TO PROCESSING

By registering on one of our Web sites, you consent to the transmission of your information to, and its collection and processing in, the United States, and any other jurisdiction, in accordance with this policy.

YOUR ACCESS RIGHTS

You may be able to access, view, delete and change your preferences, profile, and other information by visiting  [ **My Account**](http://www.ems.com/my-account.html)

YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

California law permits our customers who are California residents to request certain information about our disclosure of Personal Information to third parties for these third parties’ direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please write to us at Eastern Mountain Sports, 160 Corporate Court, Meriden, CT  06450  Attn: Customer Service---California Privacy Rights.

CONTACT US

Eastern Mountain Sports welcomes your questions and comments about privacy. Please feel free to contact us by writing to us at Eastern Mountain Sports, 160 Corporate Court, Meriden, CT  06450  Attn: Customer Service---Privacy & Security Policy
